<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Church</title>
    <link>http://markchur.ch/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark Church</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 01:01:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markchur.ch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>building a blog part 1: deploying hugo</title>
      <link>http://markchur.ch/posts/2019-05-20-building-a-blog-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 01:01:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markchur.ch/posts/2019-05-20-building-a-blog-part-1/</guid>
      <description>There are more than a few options out there to host a blog these days. But this is a technical blog and as one of my first posts, I wanted to provide a technical tutorial on how it was deployed and what I learned.
For this site, I wanted to own the full technical stack, for two reaons:
 to have full control over every functional and design aspect of the site to fully understand how the site software stack works from the operating system on up  The site is only made from open source software so if I wanted to edit some miniscule detail, I have full power to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>http://markchur.ch/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 20:24:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markchur.ch/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a product manager in the software infrastructure and networking space. I&#39;ve always been impressed by people who write content about their profession and interests. I realized two things that finally helped me start doing it myself:
 You don&#39;t have to know it all. Scope down an article until you feel comfortable enough to put it out there. Small is better than nothing. Don&#39;t feel compelled to make every post a big project, because they will never get done.  Fell free to get in touch with me on twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links</title>
      <link>http://markchur.ch/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 20:24:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markchur.ch/links/</guid>
      <description> Here are some of my favorite links around the internet.
Technology &amp;amp; Science  The Architecture of Open Source Applications - An amazingly detailed breakdown of how super common technologies work MIT Technology Review - A look ahead at the scientific progress that will trickle down as world-changing technologies in the next decade MartinFowler.com - Articles that taught me different software architecture design concepts such as backend design and decomposition to microservices Kubelist - A regularly curated list of projects and events in the Kuberentes ecosystem Julia Evans Blog - Assorted posts on Linux and networking that was actually a huge inspiration for this site Hacker News - This site gets a lot of shit for being a Silicon Valley echo chamber but I still find interesting content here on every visit  Specific Technology Posts  Site Reliability Engineering by Google - The SRE bible for running distributed systems in production Docker Internals - Deep dive in to what makes up containers and how the docker engine works Operating Systems: Three Easy Pieces - A free digital textbook that taught me the fundamentals of operating systems Packet Filtering in Linux by Purdue University - My iptables reference that I have to return to more often than I&#39;m comfortable admitting Awesome Docker - List of great Docker and Kubernetes resources  Product Management  Stratechery - A blog that perfectly blends technology with business strategy The Product School YouTube - Large set of posts from PMs talking about their work  Life  Wait but Why Mark Manson No Zero Days - Motivational trick to help create or kill a habit  Money  Stockrow - A good site for filtering and comparing different equities Bigger Pockets - Resources and community for Real Estate investing  Podcasts  Planet Money - Basically Freakonomics, but delivered weekly as bite sized stories a16z Podcast - Podcast of Andreesen Horowitz focused on technology and business trends  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>college majors determine less than you think</title>
      <link>http://markchur.ch/posts/2018-12-10-college-major-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 14:35:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markchur.ch/posts/2018-12-10-college-major-stress/</guid>
      <description>Until you’re 22 or 23, life is like a video game. Once you leave the introductory level of daycare that teaches you the what the buttons do (run, jump, kick, poop) you start on the first level of this video game — elementary school. From that point forward you’re leveling up. Everybody that started with you is (mostly) leveling up along with you on the same path and rate. You don’t even have to be that good to get to the next level, just don’t completely screw it up and they’ll let you move forward with everybody else.
After leveling for a number of years, you hit one of the most exciting parts of the game — college.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>